leedsmet.ac.uk 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Leeds Beckett University

* * *

This privacy statement covers the information and services relating to the website provided by Leeds Beckett University (Leeds Beckett) at www.leedsbeckett.ac.uk (the “Leeds Beckett Website”). 

The purpose of this statement is to inform users of the Leeds Beckett Website about what information is collected about them when they visit this site, how this information is used, any disclosure to third parties and the ways in which users' privacy is protected.

## Confidentiality and security

Leeds Beckett University takes your privacy seriously. We are responsible for looking after your personal data as Data Controller. Any information we collect will be held securely and in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and the Data Protection Act 2018 (“DPA”) and any successor legislation to the GDPR and DPA. Your personal details are not normally disclosed to any third parties. However, under certain circumstances, we may need to disclose your personal details to a third party so that:

  * we or they can provide a service you have requested;
  * we can fulfil a request for information.

Any information about you that we pass to a third party will be held securely by that party, in accordance with the GDPR and DPA, and used only to provide the services or information you have requested.

## Information we collect from visitors for our own use

We collect several kinds of information from visitors to www.leedsbeckett.ac.uk depending on the part of the site being visited: e-mail enquiries, student recruitment, e-mail addresses, site usage information and, in a few cases, personal details such as your name, email address and postal details if you order publications/documents to be sent or register for a service provided by the University (for example, the student accommodation service or Guest WiFi).

## Where we store your personal data

In order to provide the service you have requested or fulfil a request for information, the data we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, amongst other things, the provision of support services.

By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. Leeds Beckett will take such reasonable steps as necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

You should be aware that, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

If you send an enquiry by e-mail to a specific contact listed on the Leeds Beckett website, this will be passed to the relevant section of the University so that they can fulfil your information request.

If you sign up for a subscription e-mail service, we will hold the information you have provided for as long as you require access to the service requested.

If you inform us that you wish to cancel a subscription we will remove you from our mailing list and your details will be deleted from our records.

## Site usage information and cookies

Cookies are pieces of data created when you visit a site and are stored in the cookie directory of your hard drive. They generally do not expire at the end of your session. Cookies do not contain any personal information about you and cannot be used to identify an individual user. They are used to help you when you return to a website.

For example, they may enable you to return directly to a particular part of the site by 'remembering' where you last accessed. If you choose not to accept the cookies (by setting your browser to reject them), this should not affect your access to the majority of facilities available on our website.

## Where cookies are used

## Linking to other sites from the Leeds Beckett website

The Leeds Beckett website contains many links to other sites, to help you find the information you need.

These may be 'official partners' of Leeds Beckett or other third parties with information likely to be of interest and relevance to those using our website. Leeds Beckett is not responsible for the privacy practices of the organisations that operate these other sites.

You should be aware of this when you leave www.leedsbeckett.ac.uk and, if concerned, read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

## Advertising

We may use advertising on parts of the public (Internet) or private (Intranet access only) parts of the Leeds Beckett website.

No information will be passed to such advertisers or their agents about those using the Leeds Beckett website unless such users 'click through' to a specific advertiser's site and offer their personal details directly to the advertiser.

## Guest WiFi

Leeds Beckett provides free Guest WiFi to all our visitors who are welcome to use this facility. In order for you to connect to this service, we require you to provide your name and email address which will be used for the following purposes:

  * To facilitate a connection to the Guest Wi-Fi service at Leeds Beckett University;
  * To identify any active Leeds Beckett staff and students using the Guest Wi-Fi service, who will be contacted and encouraged to use the eduroam service;
  * Email addresses will be stored securely by Leeds Beckett’s network system and for no longer than 13 months.

## "Becky" the Chatbot

“Becky” the Chatbot is operated by Leeds Beckett University and uses Chatfuel and Facebook Messenger to operate. All data transfer and storage within Becky is covered by [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update), [Chatfuel privacy policy](https://chatfuel.com/PrivacyPolicy-EU.pdf) and any data submitted falls under our university terms and conditions.

The use of Becky may give access to:

  * a unique Facebook identifier
  * first name
  * last name
  * facebook image
  * gender
  * timezone
  * locale
  * your conversation history with the chatbot
  * the last button you clicked within the chatbot
  * last user freeform input
  * last visited block id
  * last visited block name

## "Leeds Beckett University Courses" Alexa Skill

The "Leeds Beckett University Courses" Alexa Skill is operated by Leeds Beckett University and uses Amazon Alexa Skills Kit to operate. All data transfer and storage within Alexa is covered by Amazon privacy policy and any data submitted falls under our university terms and conditions.

The use of the Alexa Skill may give access to:

  * UCAS points
  * First name
  * Phone number
  * UCAS code of the course applying for

## Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page so that you can remain aware of any information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with third parties.

## Further Information

Leeds Beckett University’s data protection policy (updated from time to time) is publically accessible here.

You have certain rights in respect of your personal data that we process as follows:

  * To access your personal data that we process;
  * To rectify inaccuracies in personal data that we hold about you if it is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * To request the deletion or removal of your personal data where there is no compelling reason for its continued processing;
  * To restrict the processing of your personal data in certain ways;
  * To obtain your personal data for reuse;
  * To object certain processing of your personal data;
  * To complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office about the way in which we process your personal data.

For further information or if you would like to contact us in regards to this notice please write (explaining that your interest is in the website www.leedsbeckett.ac.uk) to the:

Data Protection Officer  
Leeds Beckett University  
Calverley Street  
Leeds  
LS1 3HE
